STEPHANIE BEGLE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

0	(619) 8	341 -	6036
	(013)) T T	0030



www.linkedin.com/in/steph-begle



https://github.com/stephbegle

SUMMARY

Oddly enough, politics paved the route to software development! Studying data analysis for societal questions with computational methods while at UCSD peaked an interest in programming! Jumped into full stack development and gained hands-on experience building web apps using React, Node.js, Ruby on Rails and other useful technologies such as test driven development in both solo and pair programming environments.

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Development Student, Learn Academy

Feb 2021 - April 2021

San Diego, CA

- Devoted 480+ hours to building full stack web applications using React and Ruby on Rails with JavaScript and Ruby languages.
- Created functional web applications using API with the Rails framework.
- Developed best practices for version control of full stack applications utilizing pair and mob programming practices with peers.
- Improved applications using debugging techniques and test driven development with Jest and Rspec.

Sales Specialist, Apple, Inc.

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

La Jolla, CA

- Researched product functionalities to aid customer understanding of them with helpful analogies.
- Promoted Apple services that would be helpful for user experiences and increased insurance enrollments (AppleCare+) by about 25%.
- Helped customers understand phone service activation requirements and steps.

Chief of Marketing, All Campus Transfer Student Association at UCSD

Sept 2020 - June 2020

San Diego, CA

• Managed social media accounts and collaborated with UC departments on community development projects.

Office Manager, DFO Global Performance Commerce

June 2018 - Sept 2018

San Diego, CA

- Organized expense reports along with setting up 50+ company credit cards with major credit card companies on a monthly basis.
- Managed inventory and purchases of supplies for daily office operations.

SKILLS

Programming languages: JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, R, Python

Testing: Jest, Rspec

Frameworks: React, Ruby on Rails

Databases: PostgreSQL, Active Record

Version Control: Git Speaking languages: English, Spanish

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Political Science - Data Analytics

Sept 2017 - June 2020

University of California - San Diego | La Jolla, CA

• Study of probability, data collection, hypothesis testing, computation, and visual display of data as it applies to political and social science problems using R and Python.

Associate's Degree: Political Science San Diego Mesa College - San Diego

Sept 2017 - May 2017